[
    {
        "question": "A customer wants to:\n- run application software\n- store related data in central computer systems\n- provide customers or other users access to them through the Internet\nWhat would help do this?",
        "options": [
            "Application architecture",
            "Application management",
            "Cloud computing",
            "IT service management"
        ],
        "answer": "Cloud computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cloud infrastructure delivers services to a specific group of organizations and individuals that share a common goal.\nWhich cloud deployment model is this?",
        "options": [
            "Community cloud",
            "Hybrid cloud",
            "Private cloud",
            "Public cloud"
        ],
        "answer": "Community cloud"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a key characteristic of PaaS (Platform as a Service)?",
        "options": [
            "No modification of the software",
            "Provides dynamic scaling",
            "Used for remote application development",
            "Vendor with advanced technical knowledge"
        ],
        "answer": "Used for remote application development"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which protocol forms the basis of the Internet and, therefore, of cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "HTTP",
            "TCP/IP",
            "SMTP"
        ],
        "answer": "TCP/IP"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main role that a network plays in cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Connecting personal computers to share computing power",
            "Connecting personal devices to the shared resources",
            "Connecting thin clients to create a pooled resource server",
            "Providing offline storage options"
        ],
        "answer": "Connecting personal devices to the shared resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does virtualization achieve?",
        "options": [
            "Virtualization creates more security than using a physical machine.",
            "Virtualization makes it easier to share resources between users.",
            "Virtualization leads to better LAN and WAN utilization.",
            "Virtualization eliminates the need for networking."
        ],
        "answer": "Virtualization makes it easier to share resources between users."
    },
    {
        "question": "Application service providers (ASPs) offered an application over a network. The application was not owned by the business.\nWhat is this an early example of?",
        "options": [
            "Arpanet",
            "Mainframes",
            "Managed services",
            "VPN (virtual private network)"
        ],
        "answer": "Managed services"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an example of a single-purpose environment?",
        "options": [
            "An accounting system on a private server",
            "An application to share documents over the Internet",
            "An interface to a large online storage application",
            "A multi-user collaboration platform"
        ],
        "answer": "An accounting system on a private server"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not a key characteristic of a multi-purpose architecture?",
        "options": [
            "Interoperable layers",
            "Multi-tiered",
            "Portability",
            "Security"
        ],
        "answer": "Security"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the abbreviation SOA stand for?",
        "options": [
            "Service-organized application",
            "Service-organized architecture",
            "Service-oriented application",
            "Service-oriented architecture"
        ],
        "answer": "Service-oriented architecture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an environment-related benefit of cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Lower bandwidth requirements",
            "Lower Internet dependency",
            "Lower levels of data protection",
            "Lower power consumption"
        ],
        "answer": "Lower power consumption"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not a limitation of cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Concerns about data protection",
            "Compliance with local laws",
            "Total costs of ownership (TCO)",
            "Lack of scalability"
        ],
        "answer": "Total costs of ownership (TCO)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flexibility can be considered both a benefit and a concern of cloud computing.\nWhich aspect is a concern?",
        "options": [
            "The absence of application customization",
            "The immediate fulfilment of new business needs",
            "The location independence for access",
            "The speed of implementation"
        ],
        "answer": "The absence of application customization"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ensures the interoperability of cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Multiple system integrators",
            "Single cloud computing vendor",
            "Standardized protocols",
            "Proprietary software"
        ],
        "answer": "Standardized protocols"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the hardware components of a local cloud environment?",
        "options": [
            "- Blade server arrays\n- LAN\n- Storage area network (SAN)\n- Network attached storage (NAS)\n- Backup and restore solution\n- Load balancer",
            "- Cloud automation software\n- Virtualization software\n- Cloud application software\n- Database software\n- Middleware\n- Operating systems",
            "- On-demand self-service\n- Broad network access\n- Resource pooling\n- Rapid elasticity and scalability\n- Measured service\n- Multi-tenancy",
            "- Security protocols\n- Encryption algorithms\n- User access controls"
        ],
        "answer": "- Blade server arrays\n- LAN\n- Storage area network (SAN)\n- Network attached storage (NAS)\n- Backup and restore solution\n- Load balancer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one of the key building blocks for a VPN (virtual private network)?",
        "options": [
            "Audits",
            "Clustering",
            "Denial of service",
            "IP tunneling"
        ],
        "answer": "IP tunneling"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which measure contributes most to data protection in cloud environments?",
        "options": [
            "Failover",
            "Role-based user profiles",
            "Service levels",
            "Virtualization"
        ],
        "answer": "Role-based user profiles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which international standard contains IT service management principles?",
        "options": [
            "COBIT",
            "ISO/IEC 22123",
            "ISO/IEC 20000",
            "NIST SP800-145"
        ],
        "answer": "ISO/IEC 20000"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does using standards benefit cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Standards ensure compliance.",
            "Standards ensure location independence.",
            "Standards ensure portability.",
            "Standards ensure security."
        ],
        "answer": "Standards ensure portability."
    },
    {
        "question": "Service level requirements (SLRs) for public clouds are highly standardized.\nWhy are they highly standardized?",
        "options": [
            "Because these SLRs are legislated and standardized by ISO/IEC",
            "Because these SLRs are legislated and standardized in the GDPR",
            "Because these SLRs are meant to be used by a large customer base",
            "Because these SLRs enable a single service level for all services"
        ],
        "answer": "Because these SLRs are meant to be used by a large customer base"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which process is not a part of service level management?",
        "options": [
            "Configuration management",
            "Human resource management",
            "Service availability management",
            "Service request management"
        ],
        "answer": "Human resource management"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is required for accessing any cloud application?",
        "options": [
            "The application and client must use the same programming language.",
            "The application must verify the user's identity.",
            "The user must know on which server the application is located.",
            "The user's browser must support the application's features."
        ],
        "answer": "The user's browser must support the application's features."
    },
    {
        "question": "To which Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) model layer do HTTP and HTTPS relate?",
        "options": [
            "2 - data link layer",
            "3 - network layer",
            "4 - transport layer",
            "7 - application layer"
        ],
        "answer": "7 - application layer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a thin client?",
        "options": [
            "A lightweight device optimized for virtualized computing",
            "A name for a desktop computer without a screen",
            "A smartphone with network access and a large processor",
            "A user terminal without a processor or a hard drive"
        ],
        "answer": "A lightweight device optimized for virtualized computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not a possible benefit of using mobile applications?",
        "options": [
            "Mobile applications synchronize e-mail and calendar automatically.",
            "Mobile devices allow access to desktop virtualizations.",
            "Mobile devices heighten the chance of shoulder surfing.",
            "There are many applications available that help staff be productive."
        ],
        "answer": "Mobile devices heighten the chance of shoulder surfing."
    },
    {
        "question": "An IT company that creates their own software switches to a PaaS (Platform as a Service) solution.\nWhat benefit does this have for the company?",
        "options": [
            "The marketing department gets an extra platform for marketing.",
            "The sales department can showcase work to clients faster.",
            "The software can be developed without software developers.",
            "The software developers can spend more time on valuable work."
        ],
        "answer": "The software developers can spend more time on valuable work."
    },
    {
        "question": "A service provider has taken over a large part of a customer’s IT systems and service management.\nHow can the service provider best show their customer that they can and will deliver most of the value chain?",
        "options": [
            "By addressing issues surrounding sizing and costing infrastructure",
            "By matching service level agreements (SLAs) with customer needs",
            "By providing access to innovative new applications and technology",
            "By showing understanding of service levels through certification"
        ],
        "answer": "By matching service level agreements (SLAs) with customer needs"
    },
    {
        "question": "An organization wishes to become a cloud service provider.\nWhich question must the organization ask themselves before becoming a cloud service provider?",
        "options": [
            "Can freed-up assets be re-used in an efficient and financially viable way?",
            "Do we need personal connections through cellphone data connections?",
            "What are the names of the customer's service desk employees?",
            "What are the provisions when we want to migrate to another provider?"
        ],
        "answer": "Can freed-up assets be re-used in an efficient and financially viable way?"
    },
    {
        "question": "Data is compromised due to unauthorized access to the data. Which threat is this?",
        "options": [
            "Account hijacking",
            "Data breach",
            "Insecure interfaces and application programming interfaces (APIs)",
            "Malware attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Data breach"
    },
    {
        "question": "A business implements two-factor authentication and monitoring of user behavior. Which risk will these measures help mitigate most directly?",
        "options": [
            "Account hijacking",
            "Data breach",
            "Insecure interfaces and application programming interfaces (APIs)",
            "Phishing attacks"
        ],
        "answer": "Account hijacking"
    },
    {
        "question": "A business frequently deals with data breaches due to insider threats. Which risk-mitigating measure is most effective for this business?",
        "options": [
            "Awareness campaigns",
            "Designing for security",
            "Implement two-factor authentication",
            "Encryption"
        ],
        "answer": "Awareness campaigns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does federated identity management do?",
        "options": [
            "It allows passwords to be used on multiple devices.",
            "It allows users to reset their own passwords.",
            "It ensures passwords are only used once.",
            "It enables the single sign-on (SSO) feature."
        ],
        "answer": "It enables the single sign-on (SSO) feature."
    },
    {
        "question": "Presence and location determine the available services and capabilities. Which characteristic of identity management is this?",
        "options": [
            "Digital identity",
            "Group management",
            "Role management",
            "Separation of duties"
        ],
        "answer": "Digital identity"
    },
    {
        "question": "The European Parliament and the Council of the European Union have drafted this legislation for data protection which came into effect in 2018. Which legislation is meant?",
        "options": [
            "The CLOUD Act",
            "The Constitution",
            "The GDPR",
            "The UDHR"
        ],
        "answer": "The GDPR"
    },
    {
        "question": "Free cloud applications may use personal data to provide personalized advertisements. What should the user be concerned about?",
        "options": [
            "The correctness of their personal data",
            "The integrity of their personal data",
            "The security of their personal data",
            "The usability of their personal data"
        ],
        "answer": "The security of their personal data"
    },
    {
        "question": "A business starts using cloud computing solutions. They recalculate their capital expenditure (CAPEX) and operational expenditure (OPEX). What is the most likely result of this re-calculation?",
        "options": [
            "Both CAPEX and OPEX decrease.",
            "CAPEX decreases and OPEX increases.",
            "CAPEX increases and OPEX decreases.",
            "Both CAPEX and OPEX increase."
        ],
        "answer": "CAPEX decreases and OPEX increases."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which benefit would a start-up company especially have from moving to cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Lower operational expenditures (OPEX)",
            "Lower operational support costs",
            "Shorter implementation times",
            "Shorter use of cloud solutions"
        ],
        "answer": "Shorter implementation times"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is a short time to market a benefit of cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Increased capacity or new technology can be implemented in a short time.",
            "Market leadership is guaranteed by implementing emerging technologies.",
            "Short time to market enables scalability and elasticity of cloud solutions.",
            "Slower worldwide coverage reduces the risks of short deployment times."
        ],
        "answer": "Increased capacity or new technology can be implemented in a short time."
    },
    {
        "question": "A business is researching cloud service providers. They are concerned about cloud security. Which question addresses this?",
        "options": [
            "Can the cloud services support the business?",
            "How does cloud security level compare to your own?",
            "What are the cloud service billing mechanism and units?",
            "What is the system performance of the cloud solution?"
        ],
        "answer": "How does cloud security level compare to your own?"
    },
    {
        "question": "A business has chosen a SaaS (Software as a Service) solution. They need to monitor the cloud service provider's financial performance. What helps a business monitor financial performance?",
        "options": [
            "Weekly technical performance reports",
            "Monthly capacity utilization reports",
            "Yearly third-party audit reports",
            "Daily user activity reports"
        ],
        "answer": "Monthly capacity utilization reports"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a good question to ask a prospective Cloud provider?",
        "options": [
            "How can we access the servers in case of an incident?",
            "How is data partitioning done?",
            "What are the names of the Service desk employees?",
            "What are the provisions when a service ends?"
        ],
        "answer": "What are the provisions when a service ends?"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the implication on storage availability of moving to a Cloud environment?",
        "options": [
            "storage capability can be easily added",
            "storage capability is expensive",
            "storage capability is limited",
            "storage capability needs to be integrated"
        ],
        "answer": "storage capability can be easily added"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is currently the most common network topology?",
        "options": [
            "Hybrid",
            "Point-to-point",
            "Ring",
            "Star"
        ],
        "answer": "Star"
    },
    {
        "question": "Capacity management is a process to ensure IT infrastructure is used efficiently and that it is provided at the right time and price in the needed volumes. Which ISO/IEC 20000 process group does Capacity management belong to?",
        "options": [
            "Control processes",
            "Resolution processes",
            "Relationship processes",
            "Service delivery processes"
        ],
        "answer": "Service delivery processes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique allows multiple operating systems to run on a single host computer?",
        "options": [
            "client",
            "Hypervisor",
            "sandboxing",
            "server"
        ],
        "answer": "Hypervisor"
    },
    {
        "question": "How might moving to the Cloud have a negative impact on users?",
        "options": [
            "Development is no longer in house and may take longer to be performed.",
            "Software licensing is no longer part of operations.",
            "Support and maintenance are no longer in house and may take longer to be performed.",
            "Uptimes can be guaranteed but not adjusted in a flexible manner."
        ],
        "answer": "Development is no longer in house and may take longer to be performed."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the single point of truth in a Claim-based identity management solution?",
        "options": [
            "the cloud application",
            "the Hypervisor",
            "the identity provider",
            "the server hosting the application"
        ],
        "answer": "the identity provider"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a major benefit of using applications on mobile devices?",
        "options": [
            "Mobile devices are cheaper than personal computers.",
            "Mobile devices provide location independence.",
            "Mobile devices uniquely identify the user approaching the application",
            "Mobile devises are more secure than personal computers."
        ],
        "answer": "Mobile devices provide location independence."
    },
    {
        "question": "The three elements that form the security corner stone of IP based network management and policy administration are the so-called Triple-A . What is not one of the Triple-A elements?",
        "options": [
            "Accounting",
            "Application",
            "Authentication",
            "Authorization"
        ],
        "answer": "Application"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the functions supported by HTTP?",
        "options": [
            "Command Fill Add Use",
            "Get Post Put Delete",
            "Order Retrieve Send Replace",
            "Receive View Select Send"
        ],
        "answer": "Get Post Put Delete"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are multiple sites often used in Cloud computing environments?",
        "options": [
            "They make network configuration easier.",
            "They can help in disaster prevention and recovery.",
            "They make it easier to virtualize IT resources.",
            "They are less vulnerable to security attacks."
        ],
        "answer": "They can help in disaster prevention and recovery."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one of the requirements for successfully using a Web-based application?",
        "options": [
            "ample client storage capacity",
            "control of user identity",
            "Service level agreements (SLAs)",
            "sufficient bandwidth"
        ],
        "answer": "sufficient bandwidth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why can virus scanning software not run directly on the hypervisor?",
        "options": [
            "because the hypervisor is hidden software",
            "because the hypervisor only guests other operating systems",
            "because the hypervisor runs on a server",
            "because the hypervisor starts up before the virus scanning software"
        ],
        "answer": "because the hypervisor only guests other operating systems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a benefit of virtual client operating systems in protection against virus infections?",
        "options": [
            "A virus infection in one operating system will not infect the other operating systems.",
            "One virus scanner on a client operating system will protect all other operating systems.",
            "The client operating systems are virtual and cannot be infected from outside.",
            "The client operating systems can be protected by the virus scanner of the host operating system."
        ],
        "answer": "A virus infection in one operating system will not infect the other operating systems."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not a key characteristic of multipurpose architecture?",
        "options": [
            "Multi-tiered",
            "Open standards",
            "Security",
            "Server virtualization"
        ],
        "answer": "Security"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a driver for Cloud Computing?",
        "options": [
            "It makes it easier to scale down IT resources.",
            "It makes an organization less dependent on the network.",
            "It allows organizations to invest in IT before it is needed.",
            "It makes it easier to integrate with legacy software."
        ],
        "answer": "It makes it easier to scale down IT resources."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a specific feature of Network Attached Storage (NAS)?",
        "options": [
            "NAS presents data to the user as if it is stored on a file server",
            "NAS uses the file system of the client computers.",
            "The NAS operating system does not provide security features.",
            "With NAS the file system is managed by the servers storing the data."
        ],
        "answer": "NAS presents data to the user as if it is stored on a file server"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is OpenID used for?",
        "options": [
            "to connect to multiple web-sites without using a password",
            "to identify yourself in dealing on-line with government agencies",
            "to pay on-line via your own bank account",
            "to use one account to sign in to multiple web sites"
        ],
        "answer": "to use one account to sign in to multiple web sites"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why may Service levels vary for Hybrid Clouds?",
        "options": [
            "Hybrid Clouds are constantly shifting from Public to Private Clouds.",
            "Hybrid Clouds are less reliable than Public Clouds.",
            "Hybrid Clouds are less reliable than Private Clouds.",
            "SLAs of Hybrid Clouds contain a mix of Public and Private Cloud SLAs."
        ],
        "answer": "SLAs of Hybrid Clouds contain a mix of Public and Private Cloud SLAs."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the function of the Web Tier?",
        "options": [
            "load balanced databases",
            "multiple backend application servers",
            "responding to client requests",
            "supporting the client requests"
        ],
        "answer": "responding to client requests"
    },
    {
        "question": "Presenting a user with a logical space for storing data and mapping this to the physical location where it is stored allows many systems to share the same storage device. What is this called?",
        "options": [
            "Dynamic scaling",
            "Load balancing",
            "Managed services",
            "Storage virtualization"
        ],
        "answer": "Storage virtualization"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is the Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) by Amazon a Public Cloud service?",
        "options": [
            "Amazon allows anyone with a credit card access to the service.",
            "Amazon sells books, DVD's and electronic equipment.",
            "Amazon monitors the servers 24 hours per day.",
            "Amazon is a company with publicly trade-able stocks."
        ],
        "answer": "Amazon allows anyone with a credit card access to the service."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the goal of an ISO/IEC 20000 follow-up audit?",
        "options": [
            "To change procedures and working instructions",
            "To check if the organization still fulfills the ISO/IEC 20000 requirements",
            "To implement additional processes within the Cloud provider's organization",
            "To pay specific attention to the Change management process"
        ],
        "answer": "To check if the organization still fulfills the ISO/IEC 20000 requirements"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the abbreviation IPsec mean?",
        "options": [
            "Internet Protocol Security",
            "Internet Private Section",
            "Intelligent Protocol Seconds",
            "Second Internet Protocol"
        ],
        "answer": "Internet Protocol Security"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an example of the implementation of federation?",
        "options": [
            "driver's license",
            "fingerprint",
            "information card",
            "iris scan"
        ],
        "answer": "information card"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most important feature of a virtualized environment?",
        "options": [
            "Multiple applications can be used by a single user.",
            "Multiple computers can be connected to a single network.",
            "Multiple operating systems can be used on a single hardware platform",
            "Multiple users can be active on a single network."
        ],
        "answer": "Multiple operating systems can be used on a single hardware platform"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main tool for users accessing the Cloud?",
        "options": [
            "remote desktop",
            "the firewall",
            "the web-browser",
            "the web-server"
        ],
        "answer": "the web-browser"
    },
    {
        "question": "In evaluating a Cloud service provider, which security issue is important?",
        "options": [
            "how the service provider implements and maintains security",
            "the compatibility of the virus scanners used by the vendor and in your organization",
            "the protection provided by your organization's firewall",
            "the security protocols used by other customers of the services"
        ],
        "answer": "how the service provider implements and maintains security"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is text messaging in automobiles outlawed in many countries?",
        "options": [
            "for financial reasons",
            "for safety reasons",
            "for security reasons",
            "for synchronization reasons"
        ],
        "answer": "for safety reasons"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a serious drawback in the early development of networks?",
        "options": [
            "computers being dedicated to one function",
            "computers were too complicated to be connected",
            "the low speed of the network",
            "vendors developing their own network communication protocols"
        ],
        "answer": "vendors developing their own network communication protocols"
    },
    {
        "question": "Providing a user access to an application in the Cloud requires several steps. In which step are the user's permissions determined?",
        "options": [
            "during the auditing phase",
            "during the authentication phase",
            "during the authorization phase",
            "during the verification phase"
        ],
        "answer": "during the authorization phase"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is a thin client called 'thin'?",
        "options": [
            "because it has a thin monitor",
            "because it has limited functionality",
            "because it has no memory",
            "because it has no processor"
        ],
        "answer": "because it has limited functionality"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is specific for public cloud?",
        "options": [
            "It is a client computer connected to a network.",
            "It uses both local and remote services in its implementation",
            "It uses services provided by an external service provider.",
            "The services are shared in the organization."
        ],
        "answer": "It uses services provided by an external service provider."
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a protocol analyzer be used?",
        "options": [
            "to analyze errors in the protocol syntax used in a failed message",
            "to distribute messages according to the addressing protocol they use",
            "to measure the bandwidth required for different types of transactions",
            "to prevent virus infections in the network software"
        ],
        "answer": "to measure the bandwidth required for different types of transactions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the principal function of the Hypervisor?",
        "options": [
            "identity management",
            "responding to client requests",
            "scheduling the sharing of resources",
            "virus protection"
        ],
        "answer": "scheduling the sharing of resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a main challenge for enterprises in using cell phones for collaboration?",
        "options": [
            "Applications for collaboration are limited.",
            "Collaborative applications are complicated.",
            "Employees want to use their private cell phones.",
            "Separating business data from personal data."
        ],
        "answer": "Separating business data from personal data."
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the integrity of information mean?",
        "options": [
            "It means that the access to the information is limited.",
            "It means that the information can be accessed by those users who are allowed to access it.",
            "It means that the information is accurate.",
            "It means that the information is protected."
        ],
        "answer": "It means that the information is accurate."
    },
    {
        "question": "What may be an economic benefit of Cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "a custom accounting system",
            "acceptance by employees",
            "purchasing thin clients",
            "reduced overhead"
        ],
        "answer": "reduced overhead"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an economic cloud solution for a short term project like a one time application design?",
        "options": [
            "Platform-as-a-Service",
            "Software as-a-Service",
            "Communication-as-a-Service",
            "Security-as-a-Service"
        ],
        "answer": "Software as-a-Service"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the generally accepted communication protocol on the Internet?",
        "options": [
            "Net BIOS",
            "OSI",
            "SNA",
            "TCP/IP"
        ],
        "answer": "TCP/IP"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an example of the use of location information?",
        "options": [
            "to determine the user's native language",
            "to determine whether the user is connected via a mobile platform",
            "to provide advertisements for local restaurants, determined by GPS",
            "to provide the correct version of the application for the user's operating system"
        ],
        "answer": "to provide advertisements for local restaurants, determined by GPS"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is privacy an area of concern in Cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "Data cannot be securely stored in a Cloud solution.",
            "Data always resides in another country, with different privacy laws.",
            "People using Cloud solutions are afraid that their data is not secure in the Cloud.",
            "Privacy laws vary from country to country."
        ],
        "answer": "Privacy laws vary from country to country."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which characteristic of an Identity management system attributes permissions to roles and not to people?",
        "options": [
            "digital identity",
            "group management",
            "people management",
            "self service functions"
        ],
        "answer": "group management"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is not a security measure associated with the Single Sign On (SSO) principle?",
        "options": [
            "Active directory authentication",
            "Security token",
            "SOAP protocol",
            "Smart card"
        ],
        "answer": "SOAP protocol"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one of the main risks associated with using Cloud solutions?",
        "options": [
            "Bankruptcy of the Cloud provider",
            "Constant updates to Cloud applications",
            "Having to use a password to access Cloud applications and then losing it.",
            "Having no direct access to applications or infrastructure in case of an incident."
        ],
        "answer": "Having no direct access to applications or infrastructure in case of an incident."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the benefit of replication of data center sites?",
        "options": [
            "data protection",
            "disaster recovery",
            "extended data storage",
            "increased response rate"
        ],
        "answer": "disaster recovery"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Service Model provides the best environment for testing new software?",
        "options": [
            "Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)",
            "Platform as a Service (PaaS)",
            "Software as a Service (SaaS)",
            "There is no difference"
        ],
        "answer": "Platform as a Service (PaaS)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why became the Ethernet standard popular for Local Area Networks (LANs)?",
        "options": [
            "because the Ethernet standard was fastest",
            "because the Ethernet standard was released for general use",
            "because the Ethernet standard was suitable for mainframes",
            "because the Ethernet standard was used by the largest vendor"
        ],
        "answer": "because the Ethernet standard was released for general use"
    },
    {
        "question": "How might moving to Cloud computing enhance user's ongoing experience of software applications?",
        "options": [
            "by accomplishing quick and efficient application updates",
            "by increasing the access to information available on the Internet",
            "by moving internal systems with performance problems to the Cloud",
            "by passing problems with applications to the Cloud provider"
        ],
        "answer": "by accomplishing quick and efficient application updates"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a difference between XML and HTML?",
        "options": [
            "XML is used to format many types of documents and structures; HTML formats the display of content in a web-browser.",
            "HTML is used to format many types of documents and structures; XML formats the display of content in a web-browser.",
            "HTML can be used to format the display of content in a web-browser, XML cannot.",
            "XML can be used to format the display of content in a web-browser, HTML cannot."
        ],
        "answer": "XML is used to format many types of documents and structures; HTML formats the display of content in a web-browser."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which language can be used for running programs on the client side during web access?",
        "options": [
            "HTML",
            "Java",
            "Javascript",
            "XML"
        ],
        "answer": "Javascript"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important environment related benefit of Cloud?",
        "options": [
            "Greater data protection",
            "Reduced dependency on the Internet",
            "Reduced power requirements",
            "Smaller bandwidth consumption"
        ],
        "answer": "Reduced power requirements"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Web-based Enterprise Management (WBEM)?",
        "options": [
            "a management system for distributed computer environments",
            "a protocol to manage all web-based applications of an enterprise",
            "a set of management standards based on Internet standards",
            "a web-based application to manage the enterprise resources"
        ],
        "answer": "a set of management standards based on Internet standards"
    },
    {
        "question": "The e-mail service provided by Google (Gmail) is an example of which deployment and service model?",
        "options": [
            "SaaS in a Public Cloud",
            "SaaS in a Community Cloud",
            "IaaS in a Private Cloud",
            "PaaS in a Hybrid Cloud"
        ],
        "answer": "SaaS in a Public Cloud"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do we call the threat of data compromised due to unauthorized access?",
        "options": [
            "Account service and traffic hijacking",
            "Data loss/leakage",
            "Insecure application interfaces",
            "Shared technology vulnerabilities"
        ],
        "answer": "Data loss/leakage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the intended result of a Distributed Denial of Service (DDOS) attack on a web site?",
        "options": [
            "To change the content of the site to prevent it from providing further services",
            "To distribute the content of the site to users who are denied access to its service",
            "To infect the site to distribute a virus to users, which denies them access to further services",
            "To lock users out of the site by exhausting the sites resources"
        ],
        "answer": "To lock users out of the site by exhausting the sites resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of failover?",
        "options": [
            "to automatically restart the system in case of a failure",
            "to build up a back-up while the system is active",
            "to switch over automatically to another system",
            "to work on two systems at the same time"
        ],
        "answer": "to switch over automatically to another system"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) of a Cloud solution may change and in the worst case increase. How can this happen?",
        "options": [
            "In certain cases the TCO is intentionally shortened by lack of vision on future developments.",
            "In certain cases the TCO is just not the right measure for calculating relevant costs and expenditures.",
            "In some cases customers have not acted upon a good business case.",
            "In some cases only the distribution of different components that add up to the TCO may change."
        ],
        "answer": "In some cases customers have not acted upon a good business case."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important limitation of Cloud computing?",
        "options": [
            "actuality of data",
            "inflexibility",
            "regulatory concerns",
            "volume of waste"
        ],
        "answer": "regulatory concerns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the major benefit for software developers with regard to Cloud platforms?",
        "options": [
            "Connectivity with other platforms makes it easier for users to connect to the Cloud.",
            "Software developers can design, build and test their solutions faster.",
            "Software developers do not benefit from Cloud platforms.",
            "Solutions may be marketed on any platform."
        ],
        "answer": "Software developers can design, build and test their solutions faster."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Pay as You Go Model?",
        "options": [
            "a discount for customers changing their network provider",
            "a discount for mobile connections based on the distance to the datacenter",
            "to pay for a service after ending the contract",
            "to pay for services based on their use"
        ],
        "answer": "to pay for services based on their use"
    },
    {
        "question": "In its 2010 Whitepaper the Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) identifies a number of Top threats to Cloud Computing. What is not identified by the CSA as a threat?",
        "options": [
            "abuse and nefarious use of Cloud computing",
            "insecure application interfaces",
            "lack of good Service level agreements",
            "unknown risk profile and account"
        ],
        "answer": "lack of good Service level agreements"
    },
    {
        "question": "In identity management, how might location information be used?",
        "options": [
            "to determine the user's native language",
            "to determine whether the user is connected via a mobile platform",
            "to provide advertisements for local restaurants, determined by GPS",
            "to provide the correct version of the application for the user's operating system"
        ],
        "answer": "to provide advertisements for local restaurants, determined by GPS"
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) states there are 'five essential characteristics, three service models and four deployment models' to Cloud Computing. What is an example of a service model?",
        "options": [
            "Measured service",
            "On-demand self-service",
            "Resource pooling",
            "Software as a Service"
        ],
        "answer": "Software as a Service"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the abbreviation SOA stand for?",
        "options": [
            "Service Oriented Architecture",
            "Service Oriented Application",
            "Service Organized Architecture",
            "Service Organization Agency"
        ],
        "answer": "Service Oriented Architecture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an important benefit of using a hybrid model for cloud services?",
        "options": [
            "It allows the purchaser to save money in infrastructure and licenses.",
            "It allows the separation of sensitive data from less sensitive data.",
            "It provides better performance.",
            "It provides the best client/server experience in a cloud environment."
        ],
        "answer": "It allows the separation of sensitive data from less sensitive data."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is required in order to achieve ISO/IEC 20000 certification?",
        "options": [
            "A member of ISO must always be present at the Cloud provider.",
            "Documentation alone is enough to be certified.",
            "The Cloud provider's IT systems must be upgraded to use ISO software.",
            "The Cloud provider's staff also needs to adhere to the described procedures and instructions."
        ],
        "answer": "The Cloud provider's staff also needs to adhere to the described procedures and instructions."
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the total cost of Application Ownership (TCAO) consist of?",
        "options": [
            "The total annual costs of ownership including hardware support plus some amortization costs",
            "The total annual costs of ownership including all platform costs, staffing and other internal costs",
            "The total costs of ownership including hardware support plus some amortization costs",
            "The total costs of ownership including software, hardware and services"
        ],
        "answer": "The total annual costs of ownership including hardware support plus some amortization costs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why can virus scanning software not run directly on the hypervisor?",
        "options": [
            "because the hypervisor is hidden software",
            "because the hypervisor only guests other operating systems",
            "because the hypervisor runs on a server",
            "because the hypervisor starts up before the virus scanning software"
        ],
        "answer": "because the hypervisor only guests other operating systems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does CaaS represent?",
        "options": [
            "combining applications in a single access system",
            "communication applications provided by an offsite location service provider",
            "computer maintenance services provided by an external service provider",
            "computing services provided by an offsite location service provider"
        ],
        "answer": "communication applications provided by an offsite location service provider"
    }
]